<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-02-25T16:06:29+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">SriramJ’s Blog</title><subtitle>Get all news about blockchain, cryptocurrencies, web development, artificial intelligence, virtual reality</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tech Tour D’Horizon - 1 - Explore ES2018 and much more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" Tech Tour D’Horizon - 1 - Explore ES2018 and much more" /><published>2018-02-24T11:06:57+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-24T11:06:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d%E2%80%99horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more">&lt;h1 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pic2.zhimg.com/v2-9cc023bc08ea835c2f1c736753bc5cda_r.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploring-es2018-and-es2019-book&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exploringjs.com/es2018-es2019/toc.html&quot;&gt;Exploring ES2018 and ES2019 (book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-javascript-in-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/how-to-javascript-in-2018&quot;&gt;How to JavaScript in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From command-line tools and webpack to TypeScript, Flow and beyond, let’s talk about how to use JavaScript in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vue-enterprise-boilerplate&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chrisvfritz/vue-enterprise-boilerplate&quot;&gt;Vue Enterprise Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ever-evolving, very opinionated architecture and dev environment for new Vue SPA projects using Vue CLI 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-promiseprototypefinally-in-nodejs&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thecodebarbarian.com/using-promise-finally-in-node-js.html&quot;&gt;Using Promise.prototype.finally in Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promise.prototype.finally() is now part of latest Ecmascript spec draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-promising-promise-tips&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kepta/promising-promise-tips--c8f&quot;&gt;9 Promising Promise Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;single-page-apps-with-vuejs-and-flask-state-management-with-vuex&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackabuse.com/single-page-apps-with-vue-js-and-flask-state-management-with-vuex/&quot;&gt;Single Page Apps with Vue.js and Flask: State Management with Vuex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="tour-d-horizon" /><summary type="html">JS</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Western Union to use Ripple for Money Transfers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Western Union to use Ripple for Money Transfers" /><published>2018-02-15T11:06:57+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-15T11:06:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers">&lt;p&gt;You can add Western Union to the growing list of banks and financial institutions that are test-driving Ripple, the blockchain company trying to become the go-to service for global money transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the company’s earnings call on Tuesday, CEO Hikmet Ersek told analysts that the company is experimenting with Ripple for settling transactions and for capital optimization. Western Union is also testing Ripple’s native currency, XRP, a spokesperson confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ersek’s comments, cited below, come a month after Ripple announced a tie-up with Western Union’s rival Moneygram, which is also testing XRP in money transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Western Union’s use of XRP is a major boost for Ripple as skeptics claim it is superfluous to the money transfer process and banks don’t actually need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many banks are using Ripple’s blockchain software (known as XCurrent) to keep track of their transfers, only a handful are also using a product (known as XRapid) that integrates XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption by banks of XRP is critical to the growth of Ripple—which has described it as a “strategic weapon“—and to the value of the currency, which currently has a market cap of about $42 billion, and has swung wildly since it shot up to nearly $4 in early January (it is now worth around $1.07).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Western Union CEO’s remarks about Ripple came in response to a question about the applications of cryptocurrency in money transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean is it a technology looking for a business or do you see real use cases here?” asked Susquehanna analyst James Freeman during the earnings call.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="cryptocurrency" /><summary type="html">You can add Western Union to the growing list of banks and financial institutions that are test-driving Ripple, the blockchain company trying to become the go-to service for global money transfers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2" /><published>2018-02-11T22:11:31+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-11T22:11:31+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drafting……..!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Drafting……..!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WhatsApp payment service goes live in India</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WhatsApp payment service goes live in India" /><published>2018-02-11T19:33:47+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-11T19:33:47+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india">&lt;p&gt;Whatsapp has been working on peer to peer payments for a long peroid of time. As a WhatsApp beta tester i tweeted regarding this major update last year multiple times and got fed up on not coming up for general use. Finally Facebook owned messaging company launched payment service in beta in India. Many beta users saw this feature poping up in both IOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For India users, a way to transfer money digitally is especially useful for local merchants and for friends and family to transfer funds among themselves. WhatsApp has reportedly signed up a number of Indian banks to help bolster its payments service. The company also makes use of the Indian government’s Unified Payments Interface, or UPI, framework, which allows for instant transfer between participating banks. It’s not clear when the full payments service will launch in India, or if it will make its way to Europe or North America any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="whatsapp" /><summary type="html">Whatsapp has been working on peer to peer payments for a long peroid of time. As a WhatsApp beta tester i tweeted regarding this major update last year multiple times and got fed up on not coming up for general use. Finally Facebook owned messaging company launched payment service in beta in India. Many beta users saw this feature poping up in both IOS and Android.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Startup Lino raises $200 billion to incorporate blockchain technology in Youtube</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Startup Lino raises $200 billion to incorporate blockchain technology in Youtube" /><published>2018-02-09T23:04:22+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-09T23:04:22+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube">&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley startup Lino is preparing to take on YouTube with a decentralized, collectively-owned video content distribution system that purports to cut out the middleman to more fairly compensate content creators.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Silicon Valley startup Lino is preparing to take on YouTube with a decentralized, collectively-owned video content distribution system that purports to cut out the middleman to more fairly compensate content creators.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASIC chips for crypto mining from Samsung</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASIC chips for crypto mining from Samsung" /><published>2018-02-09T22:15:23+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-09T22:15:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung">&lt;p&gt;Samsung has started manufacturing ASIC chips for cryptocurrency mining, a company spokesperson recently confirmed this news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korean media claimed that Samsung has started this move in collaboration with a Chinese distribution partner. Samsung already manufactures high capacity GPU to handle computer graphics, some which are already used for mining purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASIC place is currently dominated by China-based  Bitmain and Canaan Creative, Samsung is all set to give a tough competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How Samsung fits into this equation isn’t clear right now. At a base level, it will rival TSMC — which it knows well from competing in other industry segments — for the attention of companies that build and sell finished mining products in the market. But, if Samsung’s move brings on new partners or if it makes hardware itself, then it could enable competitors to Bitmain and co.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="cryptocurrency" /><summary type="html">Samsung has started manufacturing ASIC chips for cryptocurrency mining, a company spokesperson recently confirmed this news.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1" /><published>2018-02-03T15:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-03T15:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article introduces you to the distributed ledger technologies (DLT), this includes blockchain too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you will learn :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain and DLT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;growth-of-distributed-ledger-technologies&quot;&gt;Growth of Distributed Ledger Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get back to late nineties were computers filled the entire room. Mainframes were more centralized in nature that would serve the entire building. The access was through dumb terminals which does I/O operations without  much of storage and processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the invention of PC’s similar computational capabilities were now housed both on the clients, as well as the servers. This gave rise to ‘client-server’ architecture, which supported the development of relational database systems. Massive data sets, which are housed on mainframes, could move onto a distributed architecture. This data could replicate from server to server, and subsets of the data could be accessed and processed on clients, and then, synced back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went by, Internet and cloud architecture enabled global access using various devices.There are two major problems with cloud computing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a) users don’t own their own data, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b) remote servers are security holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a move away from cloud computing, decentralized systems like Bitcoin give explicit control of digital assets to end-users and remove the need to trust any third-party servers and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;give explicit control of digital assets to end-users and remove the need to trust any third-party servers and infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;distributed-ledger-technology-dlt&quot;&gt;Distributed Ledger Technology (DLT)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “distributed ledger” is another term for a blockchain. It distributes a database (a ledger) of transactions to all participants in a network (also called “peers” or “nodes”). There is no central administrator or centralised data storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed ledgers existed prior to Bitcoin, the Bitcoin blockchain marks the convergence of a host of technologies, including time-stamping of transactions, Peer-to-Peer (P2P) networks, cryptography, and shared computational power, along with a new consensus algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, distributed ledger technology generally consists of three basic components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;data model&lt;/strong&gt; that captures the current state of the ledger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;language of transactions&lt;/strong&gt; that changes the ledger state&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;protocol&lt;/strong&gt; used to build consensus among participants around which transactions will be accepted, and in what order, by the ledger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6WG7D47tGb0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchains&quot;&gt;Blockchains&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per wikipedia,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A blockchain, originally block chain, is a continuously growing list of records, called blocks, which are linked and secured using cryptography. Each block typically contains a cryptographic hash of the previous block, a timestamp and transaction data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My way of defining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Blockchain is typically a distributed ledger in combination with smart contracts and other assistive technologies. Distribution of ledger happens by various consensus algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt; are simply computer programs that execute predefined actions when certain conditions within the system are met. You can imagine it as a logical IF statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if(both parties agree){execute certain instructions}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consensus&lt;/strong&gt; refers to a system of ensuring that parties agree to a certain state of the system as the true state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/consensus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;consensus&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height:250px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; is constructed by sequential order of blocks, hence the name block-chain. A block refers to set of transactions that are bundled together and added to the chain at same time. In bitcoin network miners cluster unconfirmed and valid transactions into a block. Each block has a size limit and contain a given number of transactions . In bitcoin network miner nodes must solve cryptographic challenge to move to the next block. This process in known as** “Proof of Work” **and this requires significant computing power to solve cryptographic problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchain-time-stamping&quot;&gt;Blockchain Time-Stamping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timestamping is a major feature of blockchain technology. Here each block is timestamped, with every new block being reffered to the previous block. Combined with cryptographic hashes, this timestamped chain of blocks provides an immutable record of all transactions in the network, from the very first (or genesis) block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/merkle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;merkle root&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A block in the blockchain network commonly consists of following metadata :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nonce (proof of work)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Merkle Root for transactions in the block&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reference to previous block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;merkle-tree&quot;&gt;Merkle Tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Merkle tree, also known as a binary hash tree, is a data structure that is used to store hashes of the individual data in large datasets in a way to make the verification of the dataset efficient. It is an anti-tamper mechanism to ensure that the large dataset has not been changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/merkletree.png&quot; alt=&quot;merkle tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Merkle trees are used to summarize all the transactions in a block, producing an overall digital fingerprint of the entire set of transactions, providing a very efficient process to verify whether a transaction is included in a block.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difference-between-blockchain-and-database&quot;&gt;Difference between Blockchain and Database&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/Centralized_Databases_vs_Blockchain.png&quot; alt=&quot;merkle tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some key disimilarities between blockchain and traditional database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is read-only architecture, where as in database data can be  read , modifed and deleted. Every new block gets appended to the block chain by linking to the previous block’s ‘hash’. There are no administrator permissions within a blockchain that allow editing or deleting of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains were designed for decentralized applications, whereas relational databases, in general, were originally designed for centralized applications, where a single entity controls the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sriramj.xyz/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here for Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2 (permissionless and permissioned blockchain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gettysburg Address</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gettysburg Address" /><published>2018-02-02T15:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-02T15:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address">&lt;p&gt;Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in a larger sense, we can not dedicate-we can not consecrate-we can not hallow-this ground. The brave men, living and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it, far above our poor power to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us-that from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion-that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain-that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom-and that government of the people, by the people, for the people shall not perish from the earth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><summary type="html">Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Testingg</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/second-post" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Testingg" /><published>2017-11-19T15:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-11-19T15:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/second-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/second-post">&lt;p&gt;Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in a larger sense, we can not dedicate-we can not consecrate-we can not hallow-this ground. The brave men, living and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it, far above our poor power to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us-that from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion-that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain-that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom-and that government of the people, by the people, for the people shall not perish from the earth.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Abraham Lincoln</name></author><summary type="html">Fourscore and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Ghost</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Ghost" /><published>2017-07-27T15:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-07-27T15:30:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ghost</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry></feed>