<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-12T22:17:32+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">SriramJ’s Blog</title><subtitle>Get all news about blockchain, cryptocurrencies, web development, artificial intelligence, virtual reality</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Consortium Of 61 Japanese Banks To Release Instant Mobile Payment App Powered By Ripple</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/consortium-of-61-japanese-banks-to-release-instant-mobile-payment-app-powered-by-ripple" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Consortium Of 61 Japanese Banks To Release Instant Mobile Payment App Powered By Ripple" /><published>2018-03-08T00:17:15+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-08T00:17:15+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/consortium-of-61-japanese-banks-to-release-instant-mobile-payment-app-powered-by-ripple</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/consortium-of-61-japanese-banks-to-release-instant-mobile-payment-app-powered-by-ripple">&lt;p&gt;The Japanese Bank Consortium will release an instant domestic payments mobile app, “MoneyTap,” using Ripple’s technology in the fall of 2018, Ripple’s blog reported yesterday, March 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 61-bank consortium, led by SBI Ripple Asia, is representative of more than 80 percent of all of Japan’s banking assets, according to Ripple. Takashi Okita, CEO of SBI Ripple Asia, said in Ripple’s blog post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;“Together with the trust, reliability and reach of the bank consortium, we can remove friction from payments and create a faster, safer, and more efficient domestic payments experience for our customers.”&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three of the banks in the consortium, SBI Net Sumishin Bank, Suruga Bank and Resona Bank, will begin using the app this coming fall, while the rest of the banks will join in gradually. MoneyTap will allow users to make purchases 24 hours a day, every day of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple has long focused on building relationships with banks to use its payment technologies. In February, Ripple announced two new financial service partnerships; one with the Saudi Arabian Monetary Authority for use of its cross-border payment technology for banks within the country and another with Western Union, who is testing Ripple’s Blockchain-based settlement system for transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, a South Korean bank also announced that it planned on using Ripple’s cross-border payment technologies for remittances, prompted by a Japanese-based test of Blockchain-based remittances involving Ripple and SBI Group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was created along with an editor from famous blockchain magazine.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><category term="cryptocurrency" /><summary type="html">The Japanese Bank Consortium will release an instant domestic payments mobile app, “MoneyTap,” using Ripple’s technology in the fall of 2018, Ripple’s blog reported yesterday, March 6.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Tour D’Horizon - 2 - Webpack 4.0 Release, Bitcoin Core 0.16.0 Release and more of vanilla Javascript</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-2-webpack-4-0-release-bitcoin-core-0-16-0-release-and-more-of-vanilla-javascript" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tech Tour D’Horizon - 2 - Webpack 4.0 Release, Bitcoin Core 0.16.0 Release and more of vanilla Javascript" /><published>2018-03-04T08:40:38+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-04T08:40:38+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d%E2%80%99horizon-2-webpack-4-0-release-bitcoin-core-0-16-0-release-and-more-of-vanilla-javascript</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-2-webpack-4-0-release-bitcoin-core-0-16-0-release-and-more-of-vanilla-javascript">&lt;h1&gt;Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sriramj.xyz/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sriramj.xyz/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/bitcoin-core-0160-released-heres-whats-new/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Core 0.16.0 Is Released
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/chinas-crypto-exchanges-didnt-just-survive-theyre-thriving/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;China's Crypto Exchanges Are Thriving Again
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/hacker-returns-26-million-ether-months-ico-theft/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hacker Returns $26 Million in Ether Months After ICO Theft
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coindesk.com/digital-currency-group-invests-in-crypto-friendly-silvergate-bank/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Digital Currency Group Invests in Bitcoin-Friendly Silvergate Bank

&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/nokia-launches-blockchain-powered-iot-sensing-service-smart-cities/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Nokia Launches Blockchain-Powered IoT Sensing as a Service for Smart Cities
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://truffleframework.com/blog/drizzle-reactive-ethereum-data-for-front-ends&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DRIZZLE: REACTIVE ETHEREUM DATA FOR FRONT-ENDS
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://multicoin.capital/2018/02/23/models-scaling-trustless-computation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MODELS FOR SCALING TRUSTLESS COMPUTATION
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blockgeeks.com/guides/smart-contract-development/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Best Tools for Smart Contract Development
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Front-End / Frameworks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/webpack/webpack-4-released-today-6cdb994702d4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Webpack 4.0 Released !
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://propelml.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Propel: A Scientific Computing Framework for JS
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/campaigns/kendo-ui/wp-javascript-future-2018&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Future of JavaScript:
2018 and Beyond
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://alligator.io/vuejs/vue-a11y-autocomplete/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to Create an Accessible Autocomplete Component with Vue.js
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://atomiks.github.io/tippyjs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tippy.js
A lightweight, vanilla JavaScript tooltip library
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.org/how-to-build-a-real-time-todo-app-with-react-native-19a1ce15b0b3&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;How to build a real-time todo app with React Native

&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="tour-d-horizon" /><summary type="html">Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1 Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Blockchain Could Disrupt Banking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/how-blockchain-could-disrupt-banking" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Blockchain Could Disrupt Banking" /><published>2018-02-25T22:21:58+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-25T22:21:58+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/how-blockchain-could-disrupt-banking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/how-blockchain-could-disrupt-banking">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain is transforming everything from payments transactions to how money is raised in the private market. As it picks up momentum, will the traditional banking industry embrace this new technology or be replaced by it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last September, JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon took a stab at Bitcoin: “It’s worse than tulip bulbs. It won’t end well. Someone is going to get killed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lloyd Blankfein, head of Goldman Sachs echoed that thought, saying, “Something that moves 20% [overnight] does not feel like a currency. It is a vehicle to perpetrate fraud.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet at the same time, according to a survey by The International Securities Association, 55% of companies polled are monitoring, researching, or developing solutions on top of blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this very loud and public backlash against cryptocurrencies from banks begs the question: What do banks have to be afraid of?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short answer is “a lot.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology provides a cryptographically secure way of sending digital assets, without the need for trusted third parties — such as banks. Further, tools such as smart contracts promise to automate many of the tedious processes within the banking industry, from compliance and claims processing, to distributing the contents of a will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Global banking is currently a $134 trillion industry. Banks help intermediate payments, make loans, and provide credit. The promise of blockchain as a trustless, disintermediated technology is to disrupt all of that, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Payments: By eliminating the need to rely on intermediaries to approve transactions between consumers, blockchain technology could facilitate faster payments at lower fees than banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearance and Settlement Systems: Blockchain technology and distributed ledgers can reduce operational costs and bring us closer to real-time transactions between financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundraising: By providing blockchain companies with immediate access to liquidity through initial coin offerings (ICOs), the blockchain is creating a new, cryptoeconomic model of funding that unbundles access to capital from traditional financial services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Securities: By tokenizing traditional securities such as stocks, bonds, and alternative assets, the blockchain is upending the structure of capital markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loans and Credit: By removing the need for gatekeepers in the loan and credit industry, the blockchain can make it more secure to borrow money and provide lower interest rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on for a deep dive into how the blockchain could turn the traditional banking industry on its head while enabling new business models through technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-payments&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Payments&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, trillions of dollars slosh around the world via an antiquated system of slow payments and added fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work in San Francisco and want to send part of your paycheck back to your family in London, you might have to pay a $25 flat fee for the wire, and additional fees adding up to 7%. Your bank gets a cut, the receiving bank gets a cut, and you’re charged hidden exchange rate fees. Your family’s bank won’t even register the transaction until a week later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The typical cost per transaction for a money sender averages to 7.68%, which come from per-transaction fees associated with payments, like wire fees or hidden exchange rate markups. Facilitating payments is highly profitable for banks, providing them with little incentive to lower fees. Cross-border transactions, from payments to letters of credit generated 40% of global payments transactional revenues during 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/santander-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A excerpt from a leaked internal Santander document shows revenues from international money transfers, and the risk of disruption. Nearly 10% of Santander’s revenue in 2016 came from international transfers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is disrupting this system by offering a higher-security and lower-cost way to send peer-to-peer (P2P) payments — one that requires no intermediary. Because cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum are built around a public, decentralized ledger that anyone can use to send and receive money, it cuts down on the need for trusted third parties to verify transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In doing so, blockchain technology is giving people around the world access to fast, cheap, and borderless payments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin transactions can take 30 minutes or up to 16 hours — in extreme cases — to settle. That’s still not perfect, but it represents a leg up from the average 3-day processing time for bank transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-01-19-13.16.51-1024x682.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The number of confirmed Bitcoin transactions per day has grown 8x from just over 50,000 in the summer of 2014 to more than 400,000 as of 2018.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, as transaction fees can be high, developers are actively working on scaling cheaper solutions for cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum. Other cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin Cash, already have low-priced transactions. Currently, transaction fees on Bitcoin Cash are hovering at around 20 cents per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One company, TenX, is approaching the payments problem slightly differently. It has built a wallet that’s attached to a debit card, making it easy to spend cryptocurrency everywhere you normally use plastic. The company is building a distributed network to trade between different cryptocurrencies and working to integrate that network with physical cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While cryptocurrencies are a long way from completely replacing fiat when it comes to payments, the last couple of years have seen exponential growth in transaction volume for cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum. Bitcoin transaction volume grew by 118% in 2016 alone, although much of this was a function of speculative trading (and not P2P payments).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In developing countries today, blockchain promises to give billions of people around the world access to financial services. One example of this is BitPesa, a blockchain company focused on facilitating B2B payments in countries like Kenya, Nigeria, and Uganda. BitPesa handles monthly trade volumes of $10M. Compared to a whopping 9.2% fee charged on the average cross-border payment to Kenya, BitPesa is able to slash fees to 3% through the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/atlas_s1br2ehse@2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Over the past couple of years, BitPay, a payment processor for Bitcoin, has seen a sharp rise in transaction payment volume.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example is BitPay, a Bitcoin payment service provider that helps merchants accept and store Bitcoin payments. BitPay has grown its payments volume 328% in the past year, with merchants receiving north of $110M per month. Compared to the 2%-3% fee associated with credit card transactions, BitPay charges 1% per transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One big reason behind the coming disruption of the payments industry is the fact that the creaky infrastructure supporting it is just as liable to disruption — the world of clearance and settlements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-clearance-and-settlements-systems&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Clearance and Settlements Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that an average bank transfer — as described above — takes three days to settle has a lot to do with the way our financial infrastructure was built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not just a pain for the consumer. Moving money around the world is a logistical nightmare for the banks themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, a simple bank transfer — from one account to another — has to bypass a complicated system of intermediaries, from correspondent banks to custodial services, before it ever reaches any kind of destination. The two bank balances have to be reconciled across a global financial system, comprised of a wide network of traders, funds, asset managers and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to send money from a UnicaCredit Banca account in Italy to a Wells Fargo account in the US, the transfer will be executed through the Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Communication (SWIFT), which send 24 million messages a day for 10,000 financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/main-qimg-2537e5be23c111ed0e0d2cb976fac14e-c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because UnicaCredit Banka and Wells Fargo don’t have an established financial relationship, they have to search the SWIFT network for a correspondent bank that has a relationship with both banks and can settle the transaction — for a fee. Each correspondent bank maintains different ledgers, at the originating bank and the receiving bank, which means that these different ledgers have to be reconciled at the end of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The centralized SWIFT protocol doesn’t actually send the funds, it simply sends the payment orders. The actual money is then processed through a system of intermediaries. Each intermediary adds additional cost to the transaction, and creates a potential point of failure — 60% of B2B payments require manual intervention, each taking between 15-20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/c87cd72ae74b4a91b1c730ff99ae4113.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blockchain, which serves as a decentralized “ledger” of transactions, can completely disrupt this state of play. Rather than using SWIFT to reconcile each financial institution’s ledger, an interbank blockchain could keep track of all transactions publicly and transparently. That means that instead of having to rely on a network of custodial services and correspondent banks, transactions could be settled directly on the blockchain. That would help alleviate the high costs of maintaining a global network of correspondent banks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks have estimated that blockchain innovation could cut at least $20B worth of costs from the financial sector by providing better infrastructure for clearance and settlements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripple, an enterprise blockchain services provider, is the most prominent player attempting to replace SWIFT. While the company is best known for its associated cryptocurrency, XRP, this is separate from Ripple’s banking products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SWIFT messages are one-way, much like emails, which mean that transactions can’t be settled until each party has screened the transaction. By integrating directly with a bank’s existing ledgers, Ripple’s xCurrent product provides banks with a faster, two-way communication protocol that permits real-time messaging and settlement. Ripple currently has over 100 customers signed up to experiment with its blockchain network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-01-18-18.07.56-768x516.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source: Ripple&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R3 is another major enterprise blockchain player catering to banks, and wants to be the “new operating system for financial markets.” It raised $107M from a consortium of banks like Bank of America Merrill Lynch and HSBC. It’s also lost some key members, such as Goldman Sachs, which departed because it wanted more operational control over R3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While projects like Ripple and R3 threaten to disrupt players within the broader financial services ecosystem — like SWIFT or custodian banks — they’re also working with traditional banks to bring greater efficiency to the sector. Ripple and R3 seek to decentralize systems on a smaller scale than public blockchains by connecting financial institutions to the same ledger in order to increase efficiency of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain projects are doing more than just making existing processes more efficient, however. They’re creating entirely new types of financial activity. The fundraising space is perhaps the best example of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-fundraising&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raising money through venture capital is an arduous process. Entrepreneurs put together decks, sit through countless meetings with partners, and endure long negotiations over equity and valuation in the hopes of exchanging some chunk of their company for a check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the blockchain, you don’t need a platform to raise money. You don’t need venture capitalists. You don’t have negotiations. Anyone is free to raise money from anyone at any time, and anyone can invest in projects they find interesting. In the parlance of Naval Ravikant, it is “open, distributed, and liquid all the way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the blockchain, fundraising takes the form of an initial coin offering (ICO). It’s the blockchain version of an IPO. Projects sell tokens, or coins, in exchange for a cryptocurrency like Bitcoin and Ethereum. The value of the token is — at least in theory — tied to the success of its implementation in the future. Investing in tokens is a way for investors to bet directly on usage and value. Through ICOs, blockchain companies can short-circuit the conventional fundraising process by selling tokens directly to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 2017, a whopping $5.6B was raised through ICOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/ico-1-768x576.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The popularity of ICOs has exploded in 2017, with the total amount during the first half of 2017 coming to $1.13B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple immediate benefits to ICOs for blockchain companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, ICOs occur globally and online, giving companies access to an exponentially larger pool of investors. You’re no longer limited to high-net-worth individuals, institutions, and others who are able to show the government that they’re credible investors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, ICOs give companies immediate access to liquidity. The moment you sell a token, it’s priced on a 24-hour global market. Compare that to ten years for venture-backed startups. As Earn CEO Balaji Srinivasan says, “the ratio between 10 years and 10 minutes to get the option of liquidity is up to a 500,000x speedup in time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re already seeing the impact of ICOs on the fundraising market. In Q3’17, the deal size of ICOs totaled $1.3M — close to the deal size of all tech angel and seed deals that quarter at $1.4M.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2017.10.04-tech-vs.-ico-funding-768x454.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Venture capital is taking notice, with VC firms like Sequoia, Andreessen Horowitz, and Union Square Ventures all directly investing in ICOs, as well as gaining exposure by investing in cryptocurrency hedge funds. David Pakman, a partner at Venrock, says, “There’s no question that crypto will disrupt the business of venture capital. And I hope it does. The democratization of everything is what has excited me about technology from the beginning.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the ICO boom is well underway, we’re simultaneously seeing a broader decline in the market for IPOs, from 7,322 in 1996 to 3,671 in 2017. In 2016, total funds raised from US IPOs dropped to a low of $18.5B, compared to $74.4B in 2014. It’s still not table stakes — fees to investment bankers per IPO can range from 3.5% – 7%. With greater access to private capital and alternative fundraising methods such as ICOs, we can expect to see this profitable market for investment banks decline even further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/saupload_comm-number-listed-us-companies-continues-drop-05052017-lg-768x411.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of money raised by ICOs in 2017 was already over 6% of the funds raised by IPOs in the US during the same period. Low interest rates and higher regulation have made private funding more attractive to many startups than the public markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the majority of ICOs thus far have been for pre-revenue blockchain projects, we’re seeing more and more technology companies build around a paradigm of decentralization. Telegram, the messaging app, for example recently announced that it’s trying to raise $2B via ICO. Telegram offers a free service with high user growth — but its lack of revenue makes it unlikely to succeed in the public markets. The idea behind the ICO is to sell tokens to users and bootstrap a payment platform on top of the messaging network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, as blockchain advocates predict, the next Facebook, Google, and Amazon are built around decentralized protocols and launched via ICO, it will eat directly into investment banking margins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several promising blockchain companies have emerged around this space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies like CoinList, which began as a collaboration between Protocol Labs and AngelList, are helping bring digital assets to the mainstream by helping blockchain companies structure legal and compliant ICOs. CoinList has helped blockchain companies raise over $850M via ICOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/filecoin-on-coinlist-paused-august-11-2017-600x327.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Demand for Filecoin’s ICO on CoinList was so high that it caused server overload within an hour of launch. Filecoin ultimately raised over $250M via ICO.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has developed a bank-grade compliance process that blockchain companies can access through a streamlined API, helping projects ensure everything from due diligence to investor accreditation. While CoinList’s platform is designed for blockchain projects, its focus on reducing the logistical and regulatory load around fundraising is being mirrored in the public markets. Investment banks today are experimenting with automation to help eliminate the thousands of work hours that go into an IPO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And CoinList is just the start. A number of companies are emerging around the new ICO ecosystem, from Waves, a platform for storing, managing, and issuing digital assets, to Republic.co’s crypto initiative, which is aimed at helping people invest in ICOs for as little as $10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the majority of ICOs thus far have been for pre-revenue blockchain projects, they have the potential to expand much further and become a viable alternative to traditional funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still in the early stages of the blockchain, and likely in a bubble. There’s no doubt that many of these projects will fail altogether. What’s interesting is that they’re testing out uses for the blockchain that replace functions of traditional banks. That’s not just limited to company fundraising, but also to the underlying fabric of securities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-securities&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Securities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To buy or sell assets like stocks, debt, and commodities, you need a way to keep track of who owns what. Financial markets today accomplish this through a complex chain of brokers, exchanges, central security depositories, clearing houses, and custodian banks. These different parties have been built around an outdated system of paper ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to buy a share of Apple stock. You might place an order through a stock exchange, which matches you with a seller. In the old days, that meant you’d spend cash in exchange for a certificate of ownership for the share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This grows a lot more complicated when we’re trying to execute this transaction electronically. We don’t want to deal with the day-to-day management of the assets — like exchanging certificates, bookkeeping, or managing dividends. So we outsource the shares to custodian banks for safekeeping. Because buyers and sellers don’t always rely on the same custodian banks, the custodians themselves need to rely on a trusted third party to hold onto all the paper certificates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-01-31-17.32.39-768x235.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To settle and clear an order on an exchange involves multiple intermediaries and points of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, that means that when you buy or sell an asset, that order is relayed through a whole bunch of third parties. Transferring ownership is complicated because each party maintains their own version of the truth in a separate ledger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is this system inefficient, but it’s also imprecise. Security transactions take between 1 to 3 days to settle because everyone’s books have to be updated and reconciled at the end of the day. Because there are so many different parties involved, transactions often have to be manually validated. Each party charges a fee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology promises to revolutionize financial markets by creating a decentralized database of unique, digital assets. With a distributed ledger, it’s possible to transfer the rights to an asset through cryptographic tokens. While Bitcoin and Ethereum have accomplished this with purely digital assets, new blockchain companies are working on ways to tokenize real-world assets, from stocks to real estate to gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blockchain_31.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The potential for disruption is massive. The four largest custody banks in the US — State Street, BNY Mellon, Citi, and JP Morgan — each oversees over $15+ trillion worth of assets under custody. While fees are typically lower than .02%, profits come from the sheer volume of assets. Using the blockchain, tokenized securities have the potential to cut out middlemen such as custodian banks altogether, lowering asset exchange fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/custody-banking-and-emerging-kyc-needs-10-638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The four largest custodian banks in the US each manage $15+ trillion in assets under custody. Source: Trefis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, through smart contracts, tokenized securities can work as programmable equity — paying out dividends or performing stock buybacks through a couple lines of code. Finally, putting real-world assets on the blockchain has the potential to usher in broader, global access to markets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polymath is one of the blockchain companies that wants to help migrate trillions of dollars of financial securities to the blockchain. Polymath is building a marketplace and platform that helps people issue security tokens, and implement governance mechanisms to help these new tokens meet regulations. So far, Polymath has announced partnerships with SPiCE VC, Corl, and Ethereum Capital to launch security tokens on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-02-01-18.48.45-768x435.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The slide above from Polymath predicts that the market for security tokens will grow to $10 trillion by 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, financial institutions themselves aren’t sitting still. The Australian Stock Exchange announced an effort to replace its system for bookkeeping, clearance, and settlements with a blockchain solution developed by Digital Asset Holdings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last June, Chain, an enterprise-focused blockchain company successfully orchestrated live transactions between the Nasdaq and Citi’s banking infrastructure via integration. Meanwhile, Overstock’s CEO is launching a trading platform called tZero, which wants to create a blockchain-backed dark pool, or private exchange, for securities that might be listed on the Nasdaq.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While tokenized assets are a hugely promising use case for the blockchain, the biggest hurdle is regulatory. It’s still unclear if ownership on the blockchain is legally binding, while tokens remain an ambiguous term that don’t currently have legal standing. Regulatory and legislative guidance will be key to the success of these nascent projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worlds of the consumer, the financial institution, and blockchain are slowly converging. Another space where that convergence has the potential to completely upend the way finance operates today is lending and credit — a domain that’s no stranger to disruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-loans-and-credit&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Loans and Credit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional banks and lenders underwrite loans based on an inaccurate and insecure system of credit reporting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you fill out an application for a bank loan, the bank has to evaluate the risk that you won’t pay them back. They do this by looking at factors like your credit score, debt-to-income ratio, and home ownership status. To get this information, they have to access your credit report provided by one of three major credit agencies: Experian, TransUnion, and Equifax. Based on that information, banks price the risk of a default into the fees and interest collected on loans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/https_2f2fblogs-images.forbes.com2fgreatspeculations2ffiles2f20172f122fcb_qa_loanportfoliosplit_17q3-e1513710088185-768x270.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The five biggest US banks control $3.7 trillion worth of commercial lending.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This centralized system is often hostile to consumers. The Federal Trade Commission estimates that one in five Americans have a “potentially material error” in their credit score that negatively impacts their ability to get a loan. Further, concentrating this sensitive information within three institutions creates a lot of vulnerability. Last year’s Equifax hack exposed the credit information of 143M Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternative lending on the blockchain offers a cheaper, more efficient, and more secure way of making personal loans to a broader pool of consumers. With a cryptographically secure, decentralized registry of historical payments, consumers could apply for loans based on a global credit score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blockchain projects in the lending space are still in their infancy, there are a couple of interesting projects out there around P2P loans, credit, and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-02-02-16.48.52.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bloom protocol seeks to issue credit based on a track record of successful identity attestation on the network, without trusted third parties.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One project, SALT, is a lending platform for blockchain-backed loans that raised $48M via ICO. You buy a SALT token to become a member of the network, and then put up some cryptocurrency holdings as collateral. That allows you to borrow money from lenders on the platform. Pay your loan back on time, and you get your crypto back. SALT’s not starting off taking on the lending industry as a whole. Its wedge is helping people with crypto-assets get short-term cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project, EthLend, recently raised $16.2M via ICO. EthLend wants to build a decentralized peer-to-peer lending application on top of Ethereum. This is how it works: when a borrower issues a loan request, a smart contract is created with the loan amount, interest rate, and time frame. The borrower puts up tokens of EthLend as collateral. If the loan isn’t paid in time, the lender receives tokens as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celsius, another P2P blockchain company, takes less of a free-market approach. Co-founder Alex Mashinsky says: “We offer members the chance to get paid high interest when they have a positive balance in the wallet and give them access to a credit line with low interest when they run out of cash at the end of the month.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/screenshot-2018-01-18-15.40.26-768x425.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creating a blockchain-powered loan industry requires more than just platforms — it takes the development of standards and infrastructure. Development is well on its way. Dharma, for example, is a protocol for tokenized debt. It aims to provide developers with the tools and standards necessary for building online debt marketplaces. Meanwhile, Bloom wants to bring credit scoring to the blockchain, and is building a protocol for managing identity, risk, and credit scoring on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most of these projects focus on creating liquidity through loans around people’s existing crypto assets, they’re also jumpstarting the infrastructure that will enable bigger disruption in loans via blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond the hype&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disruption doesn’t happen overnight. Blockchain technology is still in its infancy, and a lot of the actual technology has yet to be perfected. Die-hard believers in cryptocurrency believe that it will replace banks altogether. Others think that blockchain technology will supplement traditional financial infrastructure, making it more efficient. One thing is clear, however: blockchain will indeed transform the banking industry.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Blockchain is transforming everything from payments transactions to how money is raised in the private market. As it picks up momentum, will the traditional banking industry embrace this new technology or be replaced by it?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tech Tour D’Horizon - 1 - Explore ES2018 and much more</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title=" Tech Tour D’Horizon - 1 - Explore ES2018 and much more" /><published>2018-02-24T11:06:57+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-24T11:06:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d%E2%80%99horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech-tour-d-horizon-1-explore-es2018-and-much-more">&lt;h1 id=&quot;js&quot;&gt;JS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://pic2.zhimg.com/v2-9cc023bc08ea835c2f1c736753bc5cda_r.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploring-es2018-and-es2019-book&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://exploringjs.com/es2018-es2019/toc.html&quot;&gt;Exploring ES2018 and ES2019 (book)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-javascript-in-2018&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.telerik.com/blogs/how-to-javascript-in-2018&quot;&gt;How to JavaScript in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From command-line tools and webpack to TypeScript, Flow and beyond, let’s talk about how to use JavaScript in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vue-enterprise-boilerplate&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chrisvfritz/vue-enterprise-boilerplate&quot;&gt;Vue Enterprise Boilerplate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ever-evolving, very opinionated architecture and dev environment for new Vue SPA projects using Vue CLI 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-promiseprototypefinally-in-nodejs&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thecodebarbarian.com/using-promise-finally-in-node-js.html&quot;&gt;Using Promise.prototype.finally in Node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promise.prototype.finally() is now part of latest Ecmascript spec draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-promising-promise-tips&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/kepta/promising-promise-tips--c8f&quot;&gt;9 Promising Promise Tips&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;single-page-apps-with-vuejs-and-flask-state-management-with-vuex&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackabuse.com/single-page-apps-with-vue-js-and-flask-state-management-with-vuex/&quot;&gt;Single Page Apps with Vue.js and Flask: State Management with Vuex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="tour-d-horizon" /><summary type="html">JS</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Western Union to use Ripple for Money Transfers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Western Union to use Ripple for Money Transfers" /><published>2018-02-15T11:06:57+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-15T11:06:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/western-union-to-use-ripple-for-money-transfers">&lt;p&gt;You can add Western Union to the growing list of banks and financial institutions that are test-driving Ripple, the blockchain company trying to become the go-to service for global money transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the company’s earnings call on Tuesday, CEO Hikmet Ersek told analysts that the company is experimenting with Ripple for settling transactions and for capital optimization. Western Union is also testing Ripple’s native currency, XRP, a spokesperson confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ersek’s comments, cited below, come a month after Ripple announced a tie-up with Western Union’s rival Moneygram, which is also testing XRP in money transfers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Western Union’s use of XRP is a major boost for Ripple as skeptics claim it is superfluous to the money transfer process and banks don’t actually need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many banks are using Ripple’s blockchain software (known as XCurrent) to keep track of their transfers, only a handful are also using a product (known as XRapid) that integrates XRP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption by banks of XRP is critical to the growth of Ripple—which has described it as a “strategic weapon“—and to the value of the currency, which currently has a market cap of about $42 billion, and has swung wildly since it shot up to nearly $4 in early January (it is now worth around $1.07).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Western Union CEO’s remarks about Ripple came in response to a question about the applications of cryptocurrency in money transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I mean is it a technology looking for a business or do you see real use cases here?” asked Susquehanna analyst James Freeman during the earnings call.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="cryptocurrency" /><summary type="html">You can add Western Union to the growing list of banks and financial institutions that are test-driving Ripple, the blockchain company trying to become the go-to service for global money transfers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2" /><published>2018-02-11T22:11:31+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-11T22:11:31+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this series you would have got some idea about distributed ledger technology  and architecture of blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With advent of bitcoin blockchain there came the need to make use of blockchain technology in different fields by limiting certain user groups with access to confidential data. New technologies are out faster than before, whatever the technology may do the end user’s main concern is safety &amp;amp; security. Here comes the need for permission in blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Private institutions like banks realized that they could use the core idea of blockchain as a distributed ledger technology (DLT), and create a permissioned blockchain (private or federated), where the validator is a member of a consortium or separate legal entities of the same organization. The term blockchain in the context of permissioned private ledger is highly controversial and disputed. This is why the term distributed ledger technologies emerged as a more general term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will get into permissioned blockchain later on our hyperledger series &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Consensus Algorithms&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">In part 1 of this series you would have got some idea about distributed ledger technology and architecture of blockchain.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">WhatsApp payment service goes live in India</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WhatsApp payment service goes live in India" /><published>2018-02-11T19:33:47+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-11T19:33:47+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/whatsapp-payment-service-goes-live-in-india">&lt;p&gt;Whatsapp has been working on peer to peer payments for a long peroid of time. As a WhatsApp beta tester i tweeted regarding this major update last year multiple times and got fed up on not coming up for general use. Finally Facebook owned messaging company launched payment service in beta in India. Many beta users saw this feature poping up in both IOS and Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For India users, a way to transfer money digitally is especially useful for local merchants and for friends and family to transfer funds among themselves. WhatsApp has reportedly signed up a number of Indian banks to help bolster its payments service. The company also makes use of the Indian government’s Unified Payments Interface, or UPI, framework, which allows for instant transfer between participating banks. It’s not clear when the full payments service will launch in India, or if it will make its way to Europe or North America any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="whatsapp" /><summary type="html">Whatsapp has been working on peer to peer payments for a long peroid of time. As a WhatsApp beta tester i tweeted regarding this major update last year multiple times and got fed up on not coming up for general use. Finally Facebook owned messaging company launched payment service in beta in India. Many beta users saw this feature poping up in both IOS and Android.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Startup Lino raises $200 billion to incorporate blockchain technology in Youtube</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Startup Lino raises $200 billion to incorporate blockchain technology in Youtube" /><published>2018-02-09T23:04:22+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-09T23:04:22+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/startup-lino-raises-200-billion-to-incorporate-blockchain-technology-in-youtube">&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley startup Lino is preparing to take on YouTube with a decentralized, collectively-owned video content distribution system that purports to cut out the middleman to more fairly compensate content creators.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Silicon Valley startup Lino is preparing to take on YouTube with a decentralized, collectively-owned video content distribution system that purports to cut out the middleman to more fairly compensate content creators.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ASIC chips for crypto mining from Samsung</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASIC chips for crypto mining from Samsung" /><published>2018-02-09T22:15:23+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-09T22:15:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/asic-chips-for-crypto-mining-from-samsung">&lt;p&gt;Samsung has started manufacturing ASIC chips for cryptocurrency mining, a company spokesperson recently confirmed this news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Korean media claimed that Samsung has started this move in collaboration with a Chinese distribution partner. Samsung already manufactures high capacity GPU to handle computer graphics, some which are already used for mining purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASIC place is currently dominated by China-based  Bitmain and Canaan Creative, Samsung is all set to give a tough competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How Samsung fits into this equation isn’t clear right now. At a base level, it will rival TSMC — which it knows well from competing in other industry segments — for the attention of companies that build and sell finished mining products in the market. But, if Samsung’s move brings on new partners or if it makes hardware itself, then it could enable competitors to Bitmain and co.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="cryptocurrency" /><summary type="html">Samsung has started manufacturing ASIC chips for cryptocurrency mining, a company spokesperson recently confirmed this news.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 1" /><published>2018-02-03T15:48:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-02-03T15:48:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced">&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article introduces you to the distributed ledger technologies (DLT), this includes blockchain too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you will learn :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blockchain and DLT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;growth-of-distributed-ledger-technologies&quot;&gt;Growth of Distributed Ledger Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get back to late nineties were computers filled the entire room. Mainframes were more centralized in nature that would serve the entire building. The access was through dumb terminals which does I/O operations without  much of storage and processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the invention of PC’s similar computational capabilities were now housed both on the clients, as well as the servers. This gave rise to ‘client-server’ architecture, which supported the development of relational database systems. Massive data sets, which are housed on mainframes, could move onto a distributed architecture. This data could replicate from server to server, and subsets of the data could be accessed and processed on clients, and then, synced back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time went by, Internet and cloud architecture enabled global access using various devices.There are two major problems with cloud computing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(a) users don’t own their own data, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(b) remote servers are security holes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a move away from cloud computing, decentralized systems like Bitcoin give explicit control of digital assets to end-users and remove the need to trust any third-party servers and infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;give explicit control of digital assets to end-users and remove the need to trust any third-party servers and infrastructure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;distributed-ledger-technology-dlt&quot;&gt;Distributed Ledger Technology (DLT)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A “distributed ledger” is another term for a blockchain. It distributes a database (a ledger) of transactions to all participants in a network (also called “peers” or “nodes”). There is no central administrator or centralised data storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributed ledgers existed prior to Bitcoin, the Bitcoin blockchain marks the convergence of a host of technologies, including time-stamping of transactions, Peer-to-Peer (P2P) networks, cryptography, and shared computational power, along with a new consensus algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, distributed ledger technology generally consists of three basic components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;data model&lt;/strong&gt; that captures the current state of the ledger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;language of transactions&lt;/strong&gt; that changes the ledger state&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;protocol&lt;/strong&gt; used to build consensus among participants around which transactions will be accepted, and in what order, by the ledger.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6WG7D47tGb0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; encrypted-media&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchains&quot;&gt;Blockchains&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per wikipedia,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A blockchain, originally block chain, is a continuously growing list of records, called blocks, which are linked and secured using cryptography. Each block typically contains a cryptographic hash of the previous block, a timestamp and transaction data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My way of defining&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Blockchain is typically a distributed ledger in combination with smart contracts and other assistive technologies. Distribution of ledger happens by various consensus algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt; are simply computer programs that execute predefined actions when certain conditions within the system are met. You can imagine it as a logical IF statement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if(both parties agree){execute certain instructions}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consensus&lt;/strong&gt; refers to a system of ensuring that parties agree to a certain state of the system as the true state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/consensus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;consensus&quot; style=&quot;width: 250px; height:250px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; is constructed by sequential order of blocks, hence the name block-chain. A block refers to set of transactions that are bundled together and added to the chain at same time. In bitcoin network miners cluster unconfirmed and valid transactions into a block. Each block has a size limit and contain a given number of transactions . In bitcoin network miner nodes must solve cryptographic challenge to move to the next block. This process in known as** “Proof of Work” **and this requires significant computing power to solve cryptographic problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchain-time-stamping&quot;&gt;Blockchain Time-Stamping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timestamping is a major feature of blockchain technology. Here each block is timestamped, with every new block being reffered to the previous block. Combined with cryptographic hashes, this timestamped chain of blocks provides an immutable record of all transactions in the network, from the very first (or genesis) block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/merkle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;merkle root&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A block in the blockchain network commonly consists of following metadata :-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Timestamp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nonce (proof of work)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Merkle Root for transactions in the block&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reference to previous block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;merkle-tree&quot;&gt;Merkle Tree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Merkle tree, also known as a binary hash tree, is a data structure that is used to store hashes of the individual data in large datasets in a way to make the verification of the dataset efficient. It is an anti-tamper mechanism to ensure that the large dataset has not been changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/merkletree.png&quot; alt=&quot;merkle tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Merkle trees are used to summarize all the transactions in a block, producing an overall digital fingerprint of the entire set of transactions, providing a very efficient process to verify whether a transaction is included in a block.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difference-between-blockchain-and-database&quot;&gt;Difference between Blockchain and Database&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/Centralized_Databases_vs_Blockchain.png&quot; alt=&quot;merkle tree&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some key disimilarities between blockchain and traditional database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain is read-only architecture, where as in database data can be  read , modifed and deleted. Every new block gets appended to the block chain by linking to the previous block’s ‘hash’. There are no administrator permissions within a blockchain that allow editing or deleting of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchains were designed for decentralized applications, whereas relational databases, in general, were originally designed for centralized applications, where a single entity controls the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.sriramj.xyz/understand-blockchain-beginner-to-advanced-part-2&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Click here for Understand Blockchain - Beginner to Advanced - Part 2 (permissionless and permissioned blockchain)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sriram Jothiswaran</name></author><category term="blockchain" /><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry></feed>